let's distinguish briefly between type one
and type two hypervisors I did not mention
this explicitly so far but we
can of course have the hypervisor on top of
the hardware and then all the operating systems
on top of the hypervisor
and this will be the type one hypervisor and
this is basically the type we are discussing
in this lecture the one we have discussed
so far and the one I'm going to discuss in
the remaining videos too
in principle you can also have a hypervisor
that sits on top of the operating system
and this might actually be the one you usually
use when you think about your own laptop with
your own virtual machines
so you have a host operating system in this
case then you have your hypervisor that is
controlled by the operating system and on
top of that type 2 hypervisor then you have
your guest operating system I try to use
as much as possible the word guest operating
system when talking about type one hypervisor
but you realize that all operating systems
there are guest operating systems because what
is really running on top of the hardware
is the hypervisor if you have a type 2
hypervisor of course you need to distinguish
host from guest operating system because one
is the real operating system that has direct
access to the hardware and
the others have the ones that are actually
controlled by the hypervisor